it's cool to have you know a different
amount of diversity and not really have
it's not just this
you've got to be really good at it
you've got to be really athletic you get
to enjoy it you know the whole along the
way regardless of your athletic ability
yeah and it's it is not like a sport
like tennis
where you need to have like really good
technique in order to get the ball over
the net
it's very easy to get the ball over the
net and pickleball so you don't have to
worry about taking all these lessons and
stuff you don't need that the first time
you go play pickleball you will have fun
knowledge is power
[Music]
ladies and gentlemen welcome hope you're
having a fantastic day i am here with
lynn cherry of pickleball fire hello
good morning how are you today
i'm doing great i'm so happy to be here
yeah yeah so we're going to talk about
pickleball today um so i think we should
start out right off the bat just
you know we can kind of assume there
might be a couple people who don't even
know what pickleball is um i was telling
one of my co-workers last night uh about
this podcast and he didn't even he
hadn't even heard of pickleball before
so it was kind of fun to describe it to
him and also as i was describing it to
him i realized i don't even know that
much about it either so i'm glad i have
you here today lin
um will you give me kind of a
how about just what is pickleball
that's the perfect place to start you
know it's a really interesting sport
that's very easy to play but it's kind
of a combination of
tennis and ping pong and badminton
and interestingly enough it's played
with a ball that's really similar to a
wiffle ball which is one of the things
that makes it easy to play and you don't
use a racket that has been strung like a
tennis racket or a racquetball racket or
even a badminton racket
it's actually a paddle
and it's uh roughly 15 8 inches by 8
inches so it's lightweight probably
weighs about 8 ounces it's really small
easy to maneuver and that's actually a
big reason why it's so fun to play the
game is you know anybody can play it
regardless of their age or
what um you know whether they've played
a sport or not
right right and so it's it's the same
thing as we have a net we have how many
people are typically um on a team is it
two verse two or
yeah
interestingly enough pickleball um the
the game has really played most people
probably 90 95 percent of people who
play actually do play doubles so you've
got a partner there on the court and the
court itself it's uh the size of a
badminton court so it's a lot smaller
than a tennis court badminton court is
about
20 by 44 feet which actually has similar
size to a racquetball court which is 20
by 40.
uh so you know it's uh it is played um
you can play singles but most people
play doubles i think a lot of it is just
because it's such a
social sport and
playing doubles it's a little bit more
like playing chess so there's actually a
lot of strategy involved you know more
so than singles singles is a little bit
more like tennis where it's about
hitting the ball hard but when you play
doubles it's really a lot more about
placing the ball in the right spot on
the court
right right okay well so so how do you
fit into this because you have a phd in
sports psychology and your master's in
physical education correct
right right so so where do you fit into
this how did you stumble into this you
know i did i literally stumbled into
this i was uh lived in texas for 25
years before moving to connecticut in
2018 so just three years ago
and i was looking for something to do
during the winter and you know since i
had always been very athletic
i just looked to see what was going on
at the local recreation center and there
was something called pickleball which i
like many people have never had never at
the time heard of the sport so i you
know look at it on youtube and i'm like
oh yeah i think especially given my
racquetball background that i would
probably really like it so
i uh shortly after i moved here you know
just a week or two after i got here it
was still a little cold outside so i
went to the local recreation center and
just kind of peeked my head in the gym
to see you know what it looked like in
in person
and as soon as i came to the door and
this is this is literally what happens
almost everywhere where you go play
pickleball as soon as i poke my head in
the door they're like oh you gotta come
in and play and i'm like i don't have a
paddle and they're like oh here you can
use mine you know try it out you know
it's just
that's the amazing thing about the sport
it's just you know people are are so
welcoming and i was so i was really
happy to be able to participate
in pickleball because a few years before
that i had torn my acl and i did not
get it surgically repaired so i was had
really stayed away from playing court
sports because of my knee problems but
it's on a small enough court that the
game actually can be really fast but it
doesn't quite require as much movement
as if you're on a bigger court like
in in tennis
um so yeah i mean as soon as i started
playing i actually started the
pickleball fire website because i was
just
so into the sport and you know that's
what you'll hear from so many people is
that you know you almost immediately
become addicted to it it's it's amazing
i mean that that friendly community that
very welcoming vibe of yeah come on in
try it out like here's my racket that's
awesome i mean that's that's how you
that's how you have a community grow
right there just uh authentically just
by being friendly and welcoming to
newcomers and stuff um is there a reason
why you didn't um get your get your knee
your acl
surgery or is that
you know what does it affect you now or
no not not really you know the reason i
didn't get the surgery
was it's um
it's a difficult surgery because i
completely tore it so i had you know
some people when they tear their acl
that anterior cruciate ligament is still
attaching you know to the to the right
places it just kind of torn mine was
completely gone so it's a very major
surgery and it's a very long recovery so
i actually
uh specifically investigated
uh
orthopedics options in terms of the
doctors
and i wanted to find somebody who didn't
just want to go in and cut i mean that's
you know orthopedic surgeons that's what
they do
and so i found somebody after doing a
lot of research who might give a little
other opinion
and and he said you know
you don't have to get it repaired and um
you know you can just go through
physical therapy the the recovery um
you know was probably almost the same
length of time you know compared to the
surgery because there's a lot of pt and
a lot of rehabilitation
and i think the last time i went to see
him i basically said well you know i've
always been really athletic can i play
court sports because it's that side to
side movement
if you've done something to your knee
that tends to be really hard on it
and he says look if the muscles
surrounding your knee are strong enough
sure and he says i have a friend who
plays indoor soccer and he never had his
repair either and he plays indoor soccer
which is you know one of the toughest
things to do you know if you've got a
knee problem so
yeah that's kind of my story i
once i started playing pickleball it was
um
you know actually my right knee has been
bothering me which is not the one that
that i injured severely but i've kind of
done my pt on that too and uh yeah i'm
pretty pretty good to go now yeah right
on so do you have a do you have a pretty
um thorough like pre-warm-up stretching
um sort of sort of exercise like how do
you make sure your body um is is ready
for for each pickleball
event you know i've actually gotten much
better at that the good thing is that
most people when they first come to the
pickleball court and they're warming up
they're hitting the ball really softly
and we call it dinking and it's
basically where you're hitting the ball
over the net
and it's landing in what we call the
kitchen and the kitchen is seven feet
from the net on both sides of the court
so the just the way most people warm up
it's perfect to really kind of you know
it's almost like dynamic stretching even
though technically it isn't because it's
just your body's in motion you're
hitting really soft shots
you know and most people are pretty darn
good about you know warming up for
a good 10 minutes which is at least what
you need
so i've i've gotten much better in terms
of
what i do
after i play you know a lot more
stretching more typical you know static
type stretching afterwards and really
working on knee exercises and hamstring
exercises and that's largely been
because my right knee has been bothering
me
uh you know even though the left one is
the one that was really severely hurt
yeah that's the thing you got to be
listening to your body like what's going
on right now what you know not only what
are my past injuries what do i need to
make sure i'm you know uh building up
those muscles around them to support
that injury but also what's going on now
right we always got to kind of check in
what am i feeling what do i need today
what do i need this week or this this
month you know getting in tune with kind
of a
how our body is continuously fluidly
always moving and changing and giving us
different feelings and and uh you know
sparking different emotions with us so
just to to um kind of tune into your
your sports psychology um uh uh brain a
little bit
the i really like how you were talking
about um support your or you you and
your physical therapist were talking
about supporting the muscles around the
injury um
i think that that's something that we we
miss often i think they're
i mean obviously there's not a blanket
statement you can give for everybody's
injuries you know and where all of our
bodies are different and different areas
of our our bodies are different
nonetheless uh
but
what does it mean to you to kind of
strengthen the muscles around an injury
because it seems like we're often kind
of told or we think it's just don't move
it completely let it heal on its own
but i kind of like once we're able to i
feel like i i would rather try to
strengthen the muscles around it try to
build up support of the area that's
injured um kind of retrain it so because
you were able to
i'd be curious to see what what the
x-rays or whatever would look like for
your acl um when it was torn and versus
now like are the muscles around it just
supporting it really well has it kind of
healed itself um
so basically my question is
what do you what do you think about this
building the muscles around the injury
rather than just staying off it don't
touch it don't move it
stay bedrest sort of thing do you see a
big difference in that
you know what i find is that
i was
with my knee
as soon as i was able to i just went to
a physical therapist i mean because the
physical therapist that i went to was
great because he believed in
building up
your your core so kind of starting from
the from the ground up
and you know the exercises actually then
were much more than just doing it for
the knee you know it was you know doing
it for the for the hip and the and the
ankle you know just kind of
strengthening
that
and even actually even up into you know
strengthening the stomach muscles and
whatnot so he had a very very
holistic approach and granted my injury
was very serious now more recently i've
gone to physical therapy for my right
knee which is was not technically torn
but i could feel my acl and it was it
was really sore
and so his approach was a little bit
different where it was much more about
strengthening you know the knee muscles
and you know making i'd like really
tight hamstrings
so i i visited a couple times and then
once i was comfortable with the
exercises i pretty much do them if not
every night every other night
and now that i've been doing them my
both my
knee pain and my really tight hamstrings
have kind of kind of gone away so
that's that's the thing is like you were
saying before being in tune with your
body
is so important because i went through a
period where my hamstring was so tight
i didn't want to tear it
and i i took a couple days off from
playing pickleball you know i just i
just walked and it was even you know
sore walking so i know if i'm sore
walking that i really do not want to be
on the pickleball court you know
straining that much and you know
creating a bigger issue so yeah you're
absolutely right just listening to your
body so important
yeah yeah like there's certainly times
to to like i was saying push past it and
you know maybe strengthen those muscles
around it when you can muster it but
there's also a time to listen your body
and rest you know give it that time to
heal on it on its own i uh i do uh i'm
running is a big thing for me i do a lot
of running um and i feel that the way
that i continuously stay able to run you
know four or five times a week
by not being sore is stretching like
stretching is so big to me you'll really
never find me these days just heading
right out the door and going for a run
without at least having 10 15 minutes of
stretching
i do some sort of some sort of you know
kind of slow movement yoga some sort of
like primitive exercises
to wake my body up and it's not just
that i'm stretching my legs right you
know i'm stretching my whole body
um i'm i'm yeah activating my core i'm
trying to get my arms in the right spot
so my shoulders aren't kind of sitting
weird during during my run so yeah i'm
always i'm always just trying to uh
pinpoint the
the um the area around stretching before
any athletic activity because years and
years ago i was kind of like a bro power
lifter guy and i didn't really stretch
and i thought it was dorky and i would
just go in there and i luckily i didn't
have any major injuries but i'm sure
like the weird sorenesses that i had or
any um
i think i could have been a lot better
athlete if i would have added in the
stretching aspect of things
um
so the the
community behind
pickleball so you know looking through
your website
it's you kind of realize that it's it's
almost a lot bigger than i thought you
know it's there's like a pro level um
there's a lot of different people you've
had ton of people on on your podcast on
pickleball fire
um so what what is this what is this
whole community like do you do you
because like i mentioned at the
beginning not a lot of people know about
pickleball or in in my world anyway a
couple people that i've talked to this
is anecdotal of course a couple people
that i've talked to don't know a ton
about pickleball um so is it's this big
this big thing it has its own community
um there's there's pros like
tell me about the the pro level do you
watch um is is it like streamed online
is there events for for the pro level
what's what's the community like for it
it's really interesting the
[Music]
pickleball never had a pro tour
until 2020 of course right during the
pandemic there were two pro tours that
launched at that time
so needless to say they didn't have a
big schedule in 2020 but with the launch
of the pro tour you definitely have you
know streaming on on youtube
and then this year there's getting to be
more regular coverage on espn
and the cbs network now prior to
the pro tour launching in
there's um
kind of the us open and then the
nationals for pickleball
and those were events where
there was some prize money but it wasn't
a lot of prize money but there was some
coverage on tv like they would take you
know from the whole tournament they'd
taken like put a hour on i think cbs
network
so really in 2021 here now
it's really exploded in terms of the
professionals and
i
i went to watch my first professional
event i happened to be in l.a visiting
my brother in burbank and there was an
event down in san clemente california
so that was put on by the professional
pickleball association and it was at a
lifetime fitness and it was a
they had like a beautiful stadium court
so that's where the featured pro matches
works it's like a stadium court for
tennis and they put three pickleball
courts on it
and so the the venue was was beautiful
and you know just being there in person
i mean the pros are
amazingly athletic
it's really interesting that's that's
probably been one of the biggest changes
over the years i was talking with um
kyle yates who's only in his mid-20s but
he started playing 10 years ago and i
think he said in 2016
was when
he realized that
you know he could probably make a living
playing pickleball now now it's not a
living based upon prize money fully at
this point it would definitely be yes i
can i can win some prize money but i can
also teach pickleball and travel around
the country and he does his own own
clinics and whatnot so he was
one of the first people to come into the
sport who was really young and really
athletic he was like a top 30 tennis
player in florida
and uh he it actually advocate that was
in high school
um
and so yeah he's was like one of the
first young athletic guys or people to
really come into the sport
and you know he just he just dominated
2016 17 and 18 and then now we've got
some some more young ones and kyle i
think he said he's like you know the the
skill level of the people has kind of
you know at the top level and the pros
has really kind of
gone above and beyond the game itself
because there there's a lot of people
there's 4.2 million people who actually
play pickleball
um that is not a small number of people
and it you know if you're in florida
you've definitely heard about pickleball
you couldn't miss it and in the
northeast it's a lot more popular here i
think because you have so many snowbirds
so they you know over the years i've
gone down to florida you go back and
forth
so
i just talked to somebody in dallas
because i've been away from dallas area
for now for three years and i'm like i
had never heard of pickleball when i was
there and he says he says lin it's it's
getting really big in austin
but dallas it's growing more slowly but
it's finally starting to grow he said
like in all of the dallas fort worth
area which is you know two or three
million people at least
there's probably four pickleball courts
now they they are playing pickleball
there they they play you know at tennis
clubs but like dedicated courts because
where i live in connecticut i can drive
15 minutes and there's you know six
dedicated courts i drive 20 minutes and
there's eight dedicated course you know
purely for pickleball so
it's um it's it's really amazing the
growth
yeah yeah it's certainly growing i mean
i imagine if we didn't have of course
the the pandemic and the lockdowns it
could have just started to kind of
skyrocket right there too you know
actually that that really helped
pickleball
yeah the new york times called
pickleball the perfect pandemic sport
because it's outdoor you've got a small
number of people on the court
so pickleball grew
during the pandemic oh that's cool yeah
really amazing yeah so so i'm actually
coming to you um from austin and two
days ago i was a uh i was driving up
kind of by the zilker park area if
you're familiar with that and uh i had
to to go around some people playing
pickleball right in front of their house
in in the street so it was pretty cool
to see because i knew that we had this
podcast coming and i recognized their uh
their paddles and so yeah there's people
playing in the streets of austin yeah
and and that's what a lot of people did
during during the pandemic because the
pickleball court's fairly small you can
set up in the street you can set up in
your driveway
you know then that's you know 20 feet
across
um that's that's another reason why they
said it was a great sport um because
it's easy it's small enough
and it's great for you know the whole
family you know anybody can play it you
know grandma who's 85 years old can play
it and you know the youngsters who are
you know four and five can play
yeah that's so great it would be really
cool to start seeing pickleball at you
know uh holiday events just be a normal
thing in america i would like to see
that um so the uh let's talk equipment a
little bit so i came from a
skateboarding background growing up i
was um manager and assistant manager at
skate shops and whatnot and to me
the the difference between say like a
walmart skateboard and what we would
sell at the at the skate shop was just
night and day it was you know if if
anybody's interested in skateboarding
i'm like hey spend the extra whatever it
is don't get that stuff like the the
walmart skateboard is not what you want
you know
they don't even have real bearings it's
it's made of all this different material
um this is it's just not not the same
thing it's differently it's pressed
differently different plies all these
things
is is there any sort of that correlation
in pickleball is there some stuff to
maybe stay away from is there worth
spending 10 more bucks to get a nicer
racket what's the equipment like in that
world
yeah it's really all about the paddle
and in terms of paddles
the thing i would not recommend is to
buy a wooden paddle
for maybe ten dollars more you can get a
graphite paddle
and that's just like your skateboarding
analogy
so
somebody in your family once you buy
those paddles is gonna enjoy the game
go ahead and spend another ten dollars
to get a paddle that's not wood anything
other than wood is you're you're good to
go
okay yeah because i would have honestly
thought would i thought i figured they
were probably wood paddles
you can still buy wood pickleball
paddles but i i don't recommend them at
all you know even for kids i really
don't recommend them
right right okay and you do it i think
you do have information um on what
equipment you recommend on your website
am i correct with that
i do i do i've got a number of reviews
of of different gear and you know just
to give people an idea
to get into the sport of pickleball um
if you're you know to buy four paddles
and a couple balls you know you can
spend fifty sixty dollars and you know
nets are a little bit more expensive but
hopefully you know there's courts nearby
but you can at least get kind of a small
10 or 12 foot net for maybe 40 50 so
just to get started you can spend 100
and for four people and you know that
pretty much will get you started
right right and that's i mean that's
probably something that that is very
helpful to do and something obviously i
want to try to push people towards with
just this podcast episode is just
getting started with it i think you know
if it sparks your interest if it's
something that sounds interesting to you
um
you know what why not give it a shot
it's a fairly inexpensive sport all
things considered comparatively to all
these other sports um
so so getting started i mean again on
your website you have i think the basics
on instructions and rules and whatnot i
believe
on your website so if someone wants they
they get you know they spend their
hundred bucks and their family gets
their uh their paddles and their balls
and their net and they set it up like
it's it's pretty pretty easy to to do
right i mean it's um
yeah absolutely yeah i mean the rules of
the game are are really easy and um you
know in terms of actually just you know
hitting the ball and whatnot
because as i mentioned a lot of the game
can be up near the net but about seven
feet from the net so there's actually a
lot of soft shots and
you know if somebody has never played a
sport it's a great sport to get into in
fact when you've got sometimes when
you're teaching beginners and they're
they haven't really didn't have a
sporting background a lot of the
instructors will just take take a ball
and have the people throw the ball
you know so not hitting it with the
paddle but just you know throw the ball
to each other underhanded because that
mimics
like a dink which is a soft shot in
pickleball so just is if you can throw
the ball underhanded over a net you can
play pickleball that's actually how easy
it is
right i like that yeah yeah and remember
it's it's played with the wiffle ball so
it wells it's like a wolf ball so the
ball is the ball's pretty light
and so it's it's you know it's not hard
on your elbows or your wrists there's
been a lot of people who actually
there's been a number of pros who i've
talked to women who
had wrist injuries and whatnot and they
could no longer play tennis
but they could play pickleball just
because everything is is lighter
right right yeah it's a lot less intense
too you know um is the so the pickleball
itself they're the wiffle ball rather
would you call it the pickleball is that
would that be proper
yeah yeah people people don't call it a
wiffle ball they call it a pickleball
okay okay yeah that would probably make
sense um what what is the is is there a
specific you know because a golf ball
for example would have a specific
dynamic or a dimensions rather than it
needs to be what's the dimensions for uh
yeah it's a little bit bigger than
a tennis ball
or a baseball but a little bit smaller
than a softball so it's kind of in
between okay okay i'm visualizing that
yeah i can see that um hey so on you on
your podcast you've had quite the
journey on your podcast i mean you're
almost at 80 episodes from what i saw on
the site what what has this been
teaching you i mean this is probably
this is a whole nother side that you've
probably got to experience you know not
just your your love and enjoyment um for
the for the sport in the community
around you for the people you're
interacting with um but now you get to
reach out to all these other different
people who you probably wouldn't have
met without without the podcast on the
website what is the podcast journey been
like for you
oh that's actually a great question you
know the path podcast was was actually
something that came out of the pandemic
you know i started it in october 2020
you know kind of moving into the cold
months in connecticut and you know we're
not going out and doing anything i was
really conservative during the
pandemic so yeah that that's how it got
started and i did have
uh journalism background so i was
comfortable
interviewing people i had done a lot of
sports reporting when i was in high
school and college
and so i was you know comfortable
interviewing people i had to learn about
some of the you know technical pieces of
actually doing a podcast
but i i early on i made that really
efficient because at the time i was uh
still working full-time at my job
and i was just doing the podcast on the
side but that's what's so great about
pickleball too is that
i i really didn't know anybody in the
industry in pickleball when i started
the podcast i didn't know any
professional players
and i started off i think interviewing
my very first interview was with what
they call a pickleball ambassador
now i had never heard of
an ambassador in the sport before and
i've played
just about every sport imaginable
but there are actually people who are
associated with the usa pickleball
association and they have to sign up
and
answer a bunch of questions and you know
basically
you know they're they're become official
pickleball ambassador and their role
is to introduce people to the sport
and they can uh you know teach beginners
and help them out actually they can't i
think officially they can't charge any
money for doing that
but um you know they're basically there
to help people get started in the sport
help grow the sport they they promote
the sport you know they'll
put put together you know drop and play
you know just where you can come anytime
and kind of arrange that and you know
like i said they often do do clinics and
whatnot
yeah yeah and that was your first ep the
first guest episode
yeah yeah that was your cat yeah that
was with kyle snake he was a
usa pickleball ambassador and he's
actually somebody who
oh man the pictures he had some great
pictures of the clothing that he wears
he like wears
these outfits on the court and we're not
talking about you know you know like
halloween outfits or anything like that
just very colorful clothing that matches
from head to toe and he's like you know
pretty
tall guy you know he's a big guy
and uh you know from
he's
he's got you know matching shoes with
his socks and shorts and shirt even his
headband
yeah great great pictures so so he's got
like this whole character that goes with
his with his pickleball ambassador-ness
yeah and and the reason he does it
is
in part of the reason he does it is
because people will come up to him on
the court you know people
feel like they can approach somebody
who's dressed like that
and you know wherever he plays or if he
goes to a tournament people will say hey
i saw your pictures on facebook i just
wanted to meet you and you know it's
just
very
you know he
very welcoming personality and and
person and that's how a lot of the
ambassadors are but although they don't
all wear the the matching clothing like
that very colorful
yeah oh how fun though i mean that
that's really cool that's uh you know
that that is a good point that you
mentioned is it does kind of open this
door it has this openness to it of when
you're wearing something like that
you're you're willing to be approached
like to kind of just talk about it so
that is cool that he's kind of the face
of what he's doing
yeah yeah he he doesn't uh hesitate to
stand out and and one of the pros who
doesn't hesitate to stand out his uh his
name is gizmo and he also has
some very colorful outfits and he told
me specifically yeah i i do this to
stand out i want people to approach me i
want to talk to them you know get to
know them you know welcome them you know
help them out teach them so that that's
you know that's pickleball that's just
how it is uh it's so fun it sounds like
such a great community honestly um i i
do
a little bit similar of something so um
the last 10 years i've been a dj
actually and i always i've always liked
fashion anyway i've kind of dressed a
bit more obtusely in a lot of ways
sometimes really colorful sometimes just
all the same color whatever
but i kind of have that where i'll wear
a certain outfit or i'll dress a certain
way and it's kind of the way of me
stepping into my character so it's i'm
wearing this thing i've got a you know
it almost is like a costume in in a
strange way but it does kind of help me
step into this okay i'm i'm now
entertaining these people they're coming
to have a good night they're coming um
you know they paid money or they're here
out out on their their night out so what
can i do to step into that entertainer
role um and so that's kind of how i add
in in outfits and whatnot but it does
kind of help you um
you know sink into what you are sink
into what you're doing you know to
wear the outfit of it um so what what
other guests have you had had on the
podcast like have you had any um you
know hopefully they're not listening but
have you had any favorites or or
episodes that were wonderful or new
things you learned from from it or oh
yeah you know from the perspective of
pickleball i i feel
i feel just so amazed because if i have
a pickleball question and need some
advice on how to do something
i'm talking to all these pros at this
point well they're not all pros believe
me but um i i can ask those questions
and get those answers so sometimes you
know in a podcast i what i find really
interesting is either to
delve really deeply into a specific
aspect of the game
you know it could be
how to hit overhead you know how to hit
a dink how to hit a drop shot you know
those are technical things if you
haven't played you know once you play
they're easy to learn so don't worry
about that
but then also there's been some really
interesting stories of people actually i
think tomorrow night i'm interviewing
somebody who lost
a hundred pounds playing pickleball what
that's awesome
yeah and uh i interviewed actually one
of the pros dropped 60 pounds playing
pickleball that i interviewed and had an
article on her in the pickleball fire
magazine
and
yeah there was also a recent podcast um
where one of the the guys who plays um
not quite at the pro level but he's he's
actually the one of the teaching pros in
the dallas area
and uh i guess he said yeah the first
couple years playing pickleball i
dropped 25 pounds and then i kind of
talked to some of the pros and they're
like well you know what do i need to do
to kind of
take the next step in my career in terms
of pickleball and they're like well
you're not fast enough so
i think he dropped another 50 60 70
pounds i mean it's because the game is
so fun
you know it's people spend a lot of time
on the court
i mean people will go
and
i've got people who when it's hot here
in connecticut they'll show up at 6 30
a.m
and but you know they'll show up you
know they'll show up at 6 30 or 7 and
they'll stay until like 10 10 30. i mean
literally they're spending three hours
on the court
and it's almost all non-stop playing so
you know sometimes it's busy and you've
got a few people you know not there
but uh you know just
three hours it's like wow so yeah you
could definitely drop some weight if
you're playing for three hours
yeah i mean i think there's really
something to be said about mixing mixing
fitness with fun you know
because a lot of times we think of okay
i've got to lose weight so i've got to
go you know run on the treadmill or do
the stair stepper for an hour and i hate
doing cardio and blah blah and i think
that it's probably actually more
difficult for our bodies like that
mind-body connection to really um
i don't know
work properly if we're kind of
internalized our internal thoughts and
our internal um uh conversation with
ourself is kind of like more negative
maybe it puts us more in the fear
response and so maybe our bodies don't
break down calories and such as well i'm
not entirely sure what i'm talking about
but um i i do like the prospect of
you know laughing and smiling and having
fun while you're doing your physical
activity while you're losing weight i
think that's really something that's
really something cool about pickleball
it is and you know
as i was saying you know people play
three hours a day
i know people who play twice a day and i
also know people who play seven days a
week twice a day and we're not talk
we're not talking about people who are
pros or anything these are just
recreational people who want to get out
there and have some fun and i totally
agree with you one of the things that i
you said you're a runner one of the
things i do not like to do is to run
and so there's there's just nothing that
you can do as much as i love sports
there's nothing that you can get me to
do to make me jog i mean it's just never
going to happen
and so you know it it's
you know if i was
you know really really heavy and needed
to lose weight that would definitely be
the last thing that i would do but the
first thing i would do would be go play
pickleball so have you you've got to go
try that you're in austin
yeah i'm definitely going to have to now
i mean i've been excited about it since
we decided to do this podcast so i'm
definitely going to be excited about it
even more now so
i'm definitely going to i'm going to i'm
going to look it up and find out and
find a little community i know i have
the uh
there's an app
in the website as well meetup.com they
have an app and you can kind of just put
your interest in there and i guarantee
if i go through there's there's
pickleball on there and i bet you
there's communities who are waiting for
for new friends to come in and join and
have some fun
that's true and actually in the austin
area they're building a couple big
pickleball complexes like very large you
know 40 50 courts
and i i believe there's already there's
already one there i'm not sure where it
is i i wasn't in texas then so i'm not
sure where it is oh i will definitely
have to get my google on and find out
about that yeah that's really cool okay
so where do you see
where do you see the sport going like
the maybe the next five years 10 years
and then also where do you see i mean
because you're doing quite a bit of
these these podcast episodes it seems
like you're really up to date on your
website it's a lot of a lot of your life
so also along with that where's
pickleball going and where do you see
yourself going with it like are you are
you going to keep riding the wave and
see where it takes you or
yeah this for me was was definitely an
unexpected unexpected wave
uh but yeah in terms of the sport itself
the the goal is to everybody wants the
sport to continue to grow
right now even though there is some
um people or
it is actually on on television and it's
certainly live streamed there isn't as
many spectators as people would like to
see in the sport
now one thing to remember about
pickleball is that
it it really became popular
for people over 50 but what's changing
now is that we've got a lot more young
people coming in
and i i have to say this and i'm
definitely included in that over 50
group is that i'm used to watching
things on tv
so
if you put it on espn i'm going to be
there watching on tv it's it's a little
harder for me to get into you know get
on and remember oh yeah it's going to be
on on youtube and it's going to be at
this time and blah blah blah so i people
really want to see the viewership grow
people want to see better prize money
for the pros you know have more sponsors
come in because there's tons of sponsors
that are pickleball related
but they're really looking for
uh people
sponsors really outside of the game you
know whether it's a credit card company
or a you know a bank or what have you
just some of the sponsors that aren't
necessarily related to pickleball
and then of course the
ultimate goal and so many people i talk
to
um
actually these are kind of two related
things is they want to get pickleball in
every school in the us
you know have that become a part of the
physical education curriculum
and it really does make sense because
it's easy to play so even if you've got
the kids who have to take pe and they're
not that athletic
they will still enjoy it so there are
juniors leagues now starting i've got a
friend who i interviewed on the podcast
adam who's got league running down in
florida and he's
working with other people throughout the
country to get juniors leagues going
and then of course the
ultimate goal is to get pickleball into
the olympics but getting a sport into
the olympics
is uh it's a long process
and they're they're really
pretty much at just at the starting
point of doing that so right they have
quite a ways to go
do you see it potentially happening what
what do you think
eventually yes yeah i mean it might not
be for 20 years
i it definitely won't be in paris
and
it
won't be in la i mean you know there
might be a presence but not officially
connected because i believe that the
exhibition sports demonstration sports
for la have already been agreed upon as
to what they are
so
maybe i'm not sure what's after la but
maybe uh maybe after la maybe an
exhibition sport but um yeah that's
definitely what people want to see and
given the growth of the game
it's uh you know it's it's gonna happen
there was um
racquetball's a sport that i played you
know when i was young and it was an
exhibition sport in the olympics a
couple times
but they never were able to take that
next step and make it a official sport
and you know i think
racquetball is a sport that was always
really male dominated
because it's you've got this
this it's a rubber ball but it's it's
hard especially if it hits you and then
you're like in this enclosed space
whereas it's almost you know normally
when you go to the pickleball courts
it's about 50 50 in terms of men and
women playing oh cool
yeah yeah so i mean yeah that's cool to
have you know a different amount of
diversity and not really have
it's not just this
you've got to be really good at it
you've got to be really athletic you get
to enjoy it you know the whole along the
way regardless of your athletic ability
yeah and it's it is not like a sport
like tennis
where you need to have like really good
technique in order to get the ball over
the net
it's very easy to get the ball over the
net and pickleball
so you don't have to worry about taking
all these lessons and stuff you don't
need that the first time you go play
pickleball you will have fun
yeah i love that i love that so okay so
someone um it looks like for me i'm in
austin so i could probably get a google
search and find um the facility we're
talking about and in some community so
how about other listeners across the u.s
if they're if they're interested they
want to go do that would you just send
them to your website first and foremost
you think
um yes on the pickleball fire website if
you go to
pickleballfire.com quartz
you will be able to find places to play
near you there's also some information
on places that have clinics you know if
you you don't necessarily need to go to
a clinic to get started but i know some
people might feel more comfortable doing
that
honestly you can just look for where
they have courts
and show up especially like at this time
of the year when it's warm out you will
you will find pickleball in the morning
usually at most places kind of seven
seven days a week although that does
vary a bit
uh but um yeah just just come to the
website and you look up courts and you
should be able to find something nearby
the courts are courts are now everywhere
even in texas
yeah yeah that's awesome i you know i
hope we can encourage more people to uh
to try out the sport you know maybe if
they've never heard of it if they want
to try it for the first time or if they
have played it maybe they played it back
in high school or whatever and they kind
of forgot about it i would i would uh i
would hope that that this conversation
could kind of
poke and prod people towards checking it
out again because that's definitely
something we need right now you know is
some form of community
obviously some athletic some athleticism
some movement you know that's that's a
good way to to keep our immune systems
and our health up up to date too you
know it's is working out and finding a
fun way to do it so um as far as far as
your website lynn what what else can we
find there i think we're kind of around
in the corner towards the end here i
just want to make sure everybody has all
the info on you where to find you um how
to listen to your podcast what else they
might be able to get from your website
and everything
great question yeah definitely come to
pickleballfire.com
you can find a link to the podcast there
where you can learn more about the game
i also have a digital magazine and you
can find that right in the main menu on
the website just says magazine it's um
free so you can get a little bit more
idea of what the sport is about and you
know learn about maybe some of the pros
and who they are just to get familiar
with the game
again you can come there and get
information on tournaments clinics
courts you can also get information on
instructors so if you are somebody who
wants to take a lesson to get started
you can just put in your zip code and
you can find somebody who is near you
i've got a pretty good list of folks who
instruct throughout the us and then
again if you just want to figure out how
to play the game
you know i have information there on
rules and i have a kind of a beginner
series that you can go through in terms
of different articles learning about the
game kind of takes you step by step kind
of one one lesson at a week
and then uh you know like you said at
the beginning of the podcast i also do
have um
information on on different products
whether it's paddles balls nets
shoes it's all it's all there so
pickleballfire.com is pretty much a
one-stop shop for anything related to
pickleball
yeah wow i love it that's so great uh
lynn i really appreciate your your time
i mean um thank you for for coming on
here and kind of giving us the lowdown
and answering my rambling questions i
appreciate it um i do have one more
question i do like to ask many of the
guests towards the end um if if you're
willing and and down for this question
what does the world need more of right
now
you know what the world
needs more of is just
people who can get along and
enjoy themselves and have fun and
you know i think that's
that that's another thing like with
pickleball is you don't see a lot of
conflict on on the court you know people
are
gracious and and and nice and try and
make the right line calls so um yeah
just you know treat each other like you
want to be treated
100 i love that answer it's great it's
amazing um again thank you so much for
your time lynn
everybody go check out pickleball fire
love yourselves drink some water stretch
take care of yourselves
go explore the community check it out
have a have a smile on your face while
you're doing that fitness thing how
about that
all right folks have a good rest of your
day lynn thanks one more time you have
good rest your day as well
if you need anything from me we'll be in
touch via email
thank you okay take care to the junkyard
love podcast
[Music]
at what age do we learn how to have
better conversations
[Music]
at what age do we learn to have better
conversations with ourselves
[Music]
no
knowledge is power
[Music]
you